Elsewhere in this domain, we saw the keywords AND
and OR used for multiple criteria within a query.
However, you may have multiple possibilities
for criteria you want within a field. For this,
instead of multiple OR conditions, you may want
to use an IN keyword. The IN keyword basically
means in one of these, as we are about to see.
Here is the same query we have used for several
examples using the WHERE clause. In this example,
we are looking for people in one of three cities:
Los Angeles, Long Beach, or Bellflower. I will add
a WHERE clause to this query and then add CITY IN
and, in parentheses, the three cities I mentioned
in single quotes and separated by commas.
I will execute this query,
and we see 380 rows, all from one of the three
cities in the criteria. Elsewhere in the domain,
we saw the NOT keyword return the opposite of a
criterion. The same holds true for the IN keyword.
If we want to see all the people outside of
these three cities, we can add the word NOT
in front of the IN keyword
(NOT IN). When I execute this,
we see everyone who is not in Los
Angeles, Long Beach, or Bellflower.